{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Which of the following represents a horizontal groove weld direction ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "1F",
        "b": "2G",
        "c": "3G",
        "d": "4F"
      },
      "explainations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "b":"You are right",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does 4F mean ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Flat groove welding position ",
        "b": "Flat fillet welding position ",
        "c": "Vertical fillet welding position",
        "d": "Overhead fillet welding position "
      },
      "explainations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"d\" is correct answer",
        "d":"You are right"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The type of joint where one workpiece is placed in an overlapping position on the other workpiece ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Butt joint",
        "b": "Groove joint",
        "c": "Lap joint",
        "d": "T joint "
      },
      "explainations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "c":"You are right",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which among the following is the most difficult welding position?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Flat ",
        "b": "Horizontal",
        "c": "Overhead",
        "d": "Vertical"
      },
      "explainations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "c":"You are right",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Double V groove welds are preferred over single V groove welds for thicker plates ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "True",
        "b": "False"
      },
      "explainations":{ 
        "a":"You are right",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which of the following is an essential element in a welding symbol ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Dimensions",
        "b": "Finish symbols",
        "c": "Reference line ",
        "d": "Tail "
      },
      "explainations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "c":"You are right",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does ‘G’ represent in basic weld symbols ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Groove weld ",
        "b": "Machining finish",
        "c": "Grinding finish ",
        "d": "Chipping finish "
      },
      "explainations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "c":"You are right",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "What does the information present below the reference line in a weld symbol refer to ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Arrow side ",
        "b": "Tail side",
        "c": "Other side ",
        "d": "Left side "
      },
      "explainations":{ 
        "a":"You are right",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }, 
    {
      "question": "What type of weld does the weld symbol ‘X’ represent ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Single Bevel Butt",
        "b": "Double Bevel Butt",
        "c": "Double V Butt",
        "d": "Single U Butt "
      },
      "explainations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer",
        "c":"You are right",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"c\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "Pick the right choice for a weld symbol ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Weld size is shown to the left and weld length is shown to the right ",
        "b": "Weld size is shown to the right and weld length is shown to the left ",
        "c": "Both weld size and weld length are shown to the right ",
        "d": "None of the above"
      },
      "explainations":{ 
        "a":"You are right",
        "b":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"a\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "The joint where the workpieces are in planes perpendicular to each other is ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Butt joint ",
        "b": "Tee joint ",
        "c": "Lap joint ",
        "d": "Edge joint "
      },
      "explainations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "b":"You are right",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    },
    {
      "question": "How is a square butt represented ?",
      "answers": {
        "a": "V",
        "b": "||",
        "c": "─",
        "d": "U"
      },
      "explainations":{ 
        "a":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "b":"You are right",
        "c":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer",
        "d":"Your are Wrong, Option \"b\" is correct answer"
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": "beginner"
    }
  ]
}
